see if I can stay on topic for five
minutes
and only five minutes blockchain to me
is not the end-all be-all solution that
it seems to be to the tech world both
open-source and blockchain are very
powerful tools I am behind I love them I
also don't think in and of themselves
their solutions because they are geared
towards a very specific demographic
which are technology people people who
already like technology or seeking it
out or trying to find the new innovative
thing but it's not the masses it's not
even looking to be a solution to the
masses it's already a barrier to entry
to say you need to be this technological
elite right to use open source that
someone else has made to use WordPress
this is it's user friendly enough but if
you're not a coder you have to pay so
much more to use WordPress than if
you're someone who understands or like
truly can get the office of open source
benefits because you can code blockchain
is similar in that the projects that
people keep pointing me towards whole
chain whole a chain and colony do seem
to be blockchain solutions which because
they have that as their sticking point
that means that if you're trying to
solve a problem you first need to run it
through blockchain as opposed to asking
what's the best solution for this what's
the best switching for us as users and
how do we create that together that's a
very different question than like it has
to be blocked Jane if your only tool is
a Hammer Every Problem looks like a nail
and so needing it to first be blockchain
is first you have to make every problem
a nail and then we're allowed to start
working on it as opposed to like no is
it a nail is it a screw is it not any of
those things at all is it you know a
bracket like we need a different
strategy and if anyone can be part of
that strategy if anyone can come be part
of a conversation as to what's not
working for them in their current life
in the current world what don't they
understand and how can we make it more
clear what isn't easy and how can we
make it more simple for them to do what
we are doing together is starting with
something and improving it I can't
improve holo chains
because I don't own them I don't know in
the individual pieces I don't own the
whole I don't understand it
and so the complicatedness of blockchain
itself that people don't understand it I
understand it more than 90% of your
average people out there I don't
understand as much as the people working
on blockchain I understand of YouTube
videos on it I'm like every time like
okay I think I got it it's complicated
no one's going to adopt a complicated
system they don't understand over one
that's for profit when they don't see
the trust and they don't see the reason
why you should trust this and on this
because there's no ledger and it's sent
well I don't cuz I own my own data that
they can get then it's like but how do I
trust you how do I know you're gonna be
here in six months I don't care about my
dad if I don't get to keep it
um there is maybe not as deeply as I
want to be able to have access to it
even if you go down right and blockchain
can solve that but it can't necessarily
convey that it solves it to the masses
it's until the mass is already on board
right oh it's so worried it's in the
cloud the next project we only use your
data wait it's the cloud thought it was
decentralized who's on your cloud
whatever whatever it's on blockchain
technology that we don't own together
because it's literally like the point is
that the developer owns it and or like
how do we make money on it that's part
of we're not even part of that
discussion you get to state
hello chain and colony you get to state
how people make money on it and there
might be a way to work on that together
but it's not designing together from the
ground up
it can't be improved by us as easily as
what I'm talking about we're literally
starting with something and looking for
constantly how do we improve it to meet
your needs it's not more powerful than
what we currently have on Facebook and
Google so it's gonna be really hard to
out-compete Facebook and Google with
their money and their power and it's not
less risky developers still have to come
on board put their time put their money
into developing something and it's a
unicorn in a Quincy a millions of
dollars or its crap and then we don't
trust the next one that comes on board
so that's where I having a system
whatever that system is to be able to
come together and create solutions
together starting with technology
because it is the most efficient it is
how we get solutions to the most amount
of people for the least amount of money
and when you improve it it's everyone
you haven't improved you have a table
and you improve it and everyone's got to
get a new table to improve it or get
that new leg that got improved whatever
it is with technology we can design it
so that no you just get it in your new
near next download probably came in to
sign actual hardware so that it's
interesting whatever swappable and
cradle-to-grave technology we're taking
we're looking at the needs of production
and make it more efficient but able to
have the tools to come together anyone
anywhere who wants to is able to come
and say what's not working for them and
work with a small group the large group
themselves to form a solution that works
for them and empowered that whatever
solution comes through there we already
own it together we already want it to
succeed and so we're gonna market it
we're gonna fund it we're gonna
problem-solve in a whole new way that we
have ownership over it then when it's
somebody else's project and all of the
blockchain projects are somebody else's
project and until we come up with a way
to at least solve the trust problem not
for the techies who understand
blockchain for everyone for your
grandmother if your grandmother asks you
why do I choose why do i why would I
trust your application over Facebook and
your answers cuz I'm your granddaughter
grandma that's not a good enough answer
we have to be able to have trust
transparency democracy all of the things
that make something we can create
together with full transparency much
more powerful and much less risky than
anything that is currently happening in
the blockchain space thank you